Guide to the Robert L. Patten literary papers, 1963-2014 MS 376
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VIII: Book, Charles Dickens and 'Boz': the birth of the industrial-age author
  - Chapter 5 (Box 17, Folder 15-17)
  - Chapter 6 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Chapter 7 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Epilogue (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Supplements (Box 17, Folder 21-22)
- Series IX: Correspondence, academic notes and ephemera
  - Barnaby Rudge (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Great Expectations, endings materials (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Oliver Twist materials and background (Box 18, Folder 3-5)
  - Nicholas Nickelby materials (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Oxford Handbook (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Basnett, Kattie (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Bassett, Troy J. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Hammond, Mary (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - O'Malley, Patrick R. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Womac, Elizabeth (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Leah Price, book review (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Mangham / Shattock papers (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Croll Lecture, Gettysburg College, April 3, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Croll Lecture and Gettysburg College information (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Dickens Project, UC, Santa Cruz, CA, July 28, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - BBC broadcast, December 29, 2011 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Lillian Nayder reference letter, 2012 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Dickens lecture, University of Kent, February 29, 2012 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Tale of Four Cities conference, 2012 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - SHARP, 2013 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Houston Seminar, 2013 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Syracuse University lecture, September 15, 2013 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - David Vincent Day lecture (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Jaya Hariprasad reference letter (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - John Southerland Festschrift (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Heather Elliott papers (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - MLS / CS courses (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Diana Hobby funeral, 2014 (Folder 18, Folder 30)
  - Patten employment papers (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Patten, annual report (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Patten, awards (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Series X: Addenda, 1964-2012
  - Sub-Series A: Entries for Oxford Companian to Dickens
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Ainsworth, Bradbury and Evans (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Browne, Buss, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Chapman and Hall (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Cruikshank, Doyle, Eytinge, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Fildes, Hone, Loving Ballad, Maclise, Meadows, Newgate novels, Seymour, Stone (2), Tenniel, Williams, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Dickens subentries—copyright, drink and temperance (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Dickens subentry—illustrators and book illustration (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Dickens subentries—legal documents, serial literature, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Entries for Oxford Companion to Dickens: Dickens subentry—publishing, writing, bookselling, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Lecture on Lewis Carroll at MFAH, [includes slides], 2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Presentations, article about Patten, 1986-1996 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1964-2011 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Research Materials, areas of interest (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series B: Patten Reviews and Articles, 1969-2010
    - Review of Martin Fido, Charles Dickens, in The Dickensian, 65 (2 copies), 1969-05 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Dickens Time and Again, in Dickens Studies Annual, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Review Essay on Paperback Editions of Oliver Twist, in Dickens Studies Newsletter, 3, 1972-09 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Review of H. J. Dyos and Michael Wolff, eds., The Victorian City: Images and Realities, in Criticism, 17 (3 Copies), Summer 1975 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Interpretations in the Midlands, Times Literary Supplement, 780, 1980-07-11 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - London Letter: Money, "The Maniac's Tear," and London's Victorian Drama, Nineteenth Century Fiction, 36 (2 copies), 1981-06 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Review of James Ayres, English Naïve Paintings, To Catch a Sunbeam: Victorian Reality Through the Magic Lantern, ed. G. A. Household, Elizabeth Glassman and Marilyn F. Symmes, Cliché-Verre, and Diana L. Johnson and George P. Landow, Fantastic Illustration and Design in Britain, 1850-1930, in Civtorian Studies, 25 (2 Copies), Winter 1982 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Review of Richard J. Dunn, David Copperfield: An Annotated Bibliography, John B. Podeschi, Dickens and Dickensiana, and Walter E. Smith, Charles Dickens in the Original Cloth, in Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 77 (2 Copies), 1983 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Review Essay on Recent Dickens Studies: 1982, in Dickens Studies Annual Essays on Victorian Fiction, 13, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Dickens: Doubles :: Twain: Twins, with Susan K. Gillman, Nineteenth-Century Fiction, 39, 1985-03 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - British Book Illustration in a European Context, in English Buchillustration I'm Europaeschen Kontext, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Review of David Kunzle, The History of the Comic Strip, II: The Nineteenth Century, in Print Quarterly, 9 (2 copies), 1992-06 (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Waltzing with Witches, Review of Contemporary Fiction, 12, Summer 1992 (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - Review of Simon Eliot, Some Patterns and Trends in British Publishing, Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 89, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - Edward Dudley Hume Johnson, in Luminaries: Princeton Faculty Remembered, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - When Is a Book Not A Book? Biblion, 4, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 29)
    - Review of Michael Slater, ed., Dent Uniform Edition of Dickens' Journalism, ANQ, 9, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 30)
    - Review of John Sutherland, Victorian Fiction, Studies in the Novel, 29, 1997 (Box 19, Folder 31)
    - Review essay, Rival Readings: Dickens and..., Studies in the Novel, 37, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 32)
    - Phizzing, Princeton Library Chronicle, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Sub-Series C: Dickens and His Publishers, Revised Edition, 2017
    - Dickens and His Publishers, rev. ed. Proofs (1 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 34)
    - Dickens and His Publishers, rev. ed. Proofs (2 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 35)
    - Dickens and His Publishers, rev. ed. Proofs (3 of 3) (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Sub-Series D: Oxford Handbook of Dickens
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Planning Correspondence, 2014-2018 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Proofs, Timeline (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Proofs, Front Matter, Chap. 1-2 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Proofs, Chap. 3-7 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Proofs, Chap. 8-10, 13 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Proofs, Chap. 36, 42-45, Index (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Adams (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Benziman (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Bodenheimer (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Bowen (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Bradley and Young (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Celikkol (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Eslick (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Glancy (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Glavin (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Groth (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Hillard (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: John (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Litwack (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Mackenzie (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: McDuffie (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Orestano (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Orford (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Perkins (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Schlicke (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Smith (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Tambling (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Tracy (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Tyler (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Vanfasse (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Varese (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Vincent (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Williams (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Oxford Handbook of Dickens, Contributor: Winter (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Sub-Series E: Dickens 200th Birthday, 2012-02-07
    - Patten's Recollections and Presentations (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Press Notices, 2011-2012 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Notices of Events (1 of 3) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Notices of Events (2 of 3) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Notices of Events (3 of 3) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Tale of Four Cities Conference, 2012-02-02-2012-02-09 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2011 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Newsletters, 2012 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Advertisements for books on Dickens (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Institute of English Studies and Charles Dickens Museum: Announcements, Calendar, Correspondence, 2011-2012 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Patten Notes for Briefing Book for Prince Charles' Appearance at Dickens Museum, 2012-02-07 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series F: Offprints (other authors)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed A-C (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed D-G (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed H (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed H (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed I, K (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed L (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 18)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed L (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 19)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed M (Box 21, Folder 20)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed P, R [no Patten] (Box 21, Folder 21)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed S (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 22)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed S (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 23)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed T, V (Box 21, Folder 24)
    - Offprints, Authors Surnamed W, Y (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Sub-Series G: Ephemera and Over-Sized
    - 10 Dickens-related Postcards (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Poster for Talk on Dickens by Kevin Brown in London, 2012-04-26 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - "Dickens in Camden" Map (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Map of East London Poverty, 1889 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Pimlico Plumbers Calendar Featuring Dickens, 2012 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Poster of Dickens' Heroes and Villains (The Guardian and Observer) (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - U. Of Buckingham Patten Nametag on Lanyard (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Royal Mint Dickens Commemorative Coin (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Commemorative Tie with Note from Cumnor House School (Box 22, Folder 9)